Nasimi Guliyev

Richmond, VA 23220

Phone: (503) 268-3766 | Email: nesimi018@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: https://github.com/guliyev | GitHub: https://github.com/guliyev

Portfolio: http://www.guliyev.com

SUMMARY

Front-End Web Developer leveraging a background in engineering. Known among colleagues for strong wit and attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project. Excited to leverage skills as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team in order to build better experiences for users.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: React, JavaScript, jQuery, Web APIs, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, IndexedDB **Back End**: Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose, mLab, MySQL, Sequelize, Passport

PROJECTS

TrendingBot App | trendingbot.com | trendingbot-code.com

- TradingBots application targets high-volume traders who want to simplify trading through a nimble interface and customizable analytics. Our application allows users to set up pre-established strategies for getting trading tips.
- Core responsibilities: UI design; HTML and CSS development; shared responsibility for JavaScript
- **Technologies used:** Bootstrap, Materialize Corporate ,Jquery UI, MomentJS, amCharts, IEX api, Stock news API

Valentinos Restaurant | valentinos.com | valentinos-code.co

- Valentino restaurant application allows the restaurant to run a paperless operation and allows managers to evaluate sales composition and monitor the efficiency of the operation real-time.
- Core responsibilities: Express routing and Sequelize queries for post routes; Heroku and JawsDB deployment
- **Technologies used:** Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, JavaScript, jQuery, Heroku, JawsDB, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Chart.js, Passport

Construction Helper | constructionhelper.com | constructionhelper-code.com

- The main purpose of the application is to help users to create their project seamlessly and post it by leaving their contact information, and during a limited time to get an offer in order to realize the project.
- Core responsibilities: : UI design; Back-end development with Express, Node.js, and MongoDB; Shared responsibility for front-end React
- **Technologies used:** MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), Mongoose, JavaScript, CSS,HTML, Heroku, mLab,

EXPERIENCE

Ellwood Thompson's

05.08.2018 – present

Sales Associate

Richmond,

VA

Sales Associate with a locally owned organic market. Responsible for dealing with customer questions about the products and discovering needs and making recommendations to build and close sales.

- Create meaningful relationships with customers to ensure they will come back.
- Maintain high-level knowledge of store products to address customer questions and concerns.
- Helped an average 70 plus customers daily.

"Azeravtoyol" OJSC

2015 - 2018

Procurement Specialist

Baku, Azerbaijan

Worked on "M4" road construction project with \$ 360 million budget financed by BNP Paribas (France).

- Prepared invitations and bid forms for contractors.
- Monitored contractor performance and recommended changes when it is necessary.
- Provided information about rules and regulating laws to organization staff members and to vendors.
- Approved bills for payment. Track the status of requisitions, contracts, and orders.

"Bank of Baku" OJSC

2012 - 2015

Loan Officer

Baku, Azerbaijan

Worked at Loan Department of the bank and were authorized to approve loan amounts from \$1.000 to \$100.000

- Answered questions of customers about types of loans and credit options that are available.
- Handle customer complaints and take appropriate action to solve them.
- Approve loans within specified limits, and refer loan applications to management for approval.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Richmond, Richmond, VA

2019 - 2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor's Degree in Science: Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University. 2007 – 2011 Graduated from Faculty of Manufacturing Automation Processes, with specialization in Automation Engineering.